weekend. It was a long uh three days, a
lot of work involved. Uh happy with the
results.
Um I'll just kind of run down these guys
that we've taken the most recent picks.
Uh Elijah Sarat from Indiana. U St.
Francis Grat as you guys know. Uh great
career at Indiana. Big body, strong
hands. Um contested catch. Probably a
guy that can play outside or inside. We
think he's really really good inside. Um
really a good back shoulder fade type of
receiver, physical, you know, just we
just think he's a really good fit for
what we want to do on offensively and
was, you know, I think speaks to us
trying to draft best available player
whenever we can and he just was really
at that point in the draft. We had some
other options, but in our mind he was
clearly the best player still available.
Um Hibner, uh we've seen him here in
Baltimore. Um he was a local local guy
for us, local proday guy um from
Virginia.
Uh Jesse knew him from his Michigan
days. Uh really think he's he's he's
really evolved uh tested really really
well at the combine. His numbers are off
the charts. Uh really really explosive,
a great jumper, really good ball skills.
Uh had an awesome year as a receiving
tight end. We think he's going to emerge
as a blocker as well. A great kid. Uh we
love spending time with him here in
Baltimore.
Uh Chandler Rivers was a guy that I I
know the scouts are really excited to
get. Undersized, very very quick,
probably fits best inside. He plays
outside, but probably fits best inside.
Uh very sticky in coverage. Again, a guy
that tested extremely well. Um his his
numbers at the combine is 40. I think
was in the four threes. He jumped really
well. Um and we've had, you know,
success over the years with these type
of guys. even going back to, you know,
some of my favorite Ravens Darius Webb
is a guy that comes to mind. Taon Young,
those those kind of really good football
players that might be a little unders
sized. Um, so we're excited about him.
Uh, and then Josh Quavvis, uh, you know,
you never can go wrong with an Alabama
tight end. Uh, he's a guy that does a
lot of different things well. He runs
good routes. He's got good hands. He's a
competitive blocker. Uh, he can align in
different spots. And I think one of our
goals this year was really coming out of
this draft with with two tight ends that
that we liked a lot. And um you know, I
think we did a good job. I really credit
uh our coaches, Zach and and uh Declan,
for really doing a great job getting
that tight end board lined up in a
really nice way for us to strategize and
make sure that we got a couple guys that
we really liked. and they weren't
necessarily, you know, players that we
had to jump into the, you know, first or
second or third round to get, but we had
options in every single round. And, uh,
and we were very fortunate to get Josh
at that point. Uh, Adam Randle's an
interesting pick. I think it is. You'll
probably see the video at some point.
It's the first draft pick that Steve
Bashad has ever made. So, uh, you know,
when we were down in Florida, Steve was
begging for a draft pick and he owns the
team. I said, "Yes, Steve." And so, um,
of course, you're gonna have a draft
pick. And so, we decided on our last
fifth round pick. Uh, he did his
research. Um, he studied the tape,
talked to people. Um, he's he's got a
really good relationship with the
Clemson head coach. Um, and Adam's a guy
as a former wide out. He's got a varied
skill set. He does a lot of different
things well. Uh, we think the best is
yet to come with him as a running back.
He's got really good hands. He can run
routes. He's a possible kick returner,
special teams guy. He's got a great body
and good measurables and we're excited
to see what he can do. He's kind of a
jack knife. Uh and he's a phenomenal
kid. We think uh one of the one of the
best makeups in this draft. Um and then
Ryan Eckley. Uh you know, Randy has been
scouring the country looking at punters
and this was his top guy. And I think
for us it was just a matter of when we
had to take them. Looking at the board,
kind of getting a sense for the teams
that might draft the punter. We knew
Buffalo was in the mix and potentially
Pittsburgh. Uh so we had to figure out
that sweet spot to get that done. And uh
the nice thing I think about, you know,
Ryan is not only is he an excellent
punter, but he's probably the best
holder in the draft, which is really
important, uh as you guys all know. So
excited to get him. Rashan Benny, um you
know, we we've actually we've coached
him, right? Lu Espazito and Jesse. Uh we
like his his frame, his skill set. He's
a guy that can play five-tech,
three-tech, physical guy, long arms,
really has a good five-tech body, which
is tough to find. He's a strong run
defender. Uh, and he fits us. He fits
our mentality, and he knows our defense,
and he's a he's a plug-and-play guy
coming in right out of the gates. Now,
last pick is Evan Bernstein.
Uh, again, a guy that plays guard. He
has played some center, not a lot. Uh,
he's he's been playing college football
for a long time. And uh he was at I
think uh South Dakota and then
Northwestern. Uh he's a guard primarily
physical, tough, gritty type of Midwest,
Big 10 type of offensive lineman. And at
that point in the draft, he was by far
the highest rated player for us and we
think he's got a good chance to help us
at some point. Questions? So Eric, when
you're when Steve's making that, why did
you select that that fifth round as the
the one that you know, was there any
kind of any backstory to why that was
the the the point in the draft that he
was going to take one?
>> I think he just he probably uh coerced
me with a nice bottle of wine down there
in Florida and we had all those picks.
We knew we were going to have all those
picks and so we just decided on that
that last pick in the fifth round.
Um, obviously maybe your best offseason
departure is Kevin Linder Balm. Um, no
obvious center in this draft, although I
guess, you know, Evan might convert. Um,
what was your overall take on this
center class available in this draft and
ultimately, you know, you even traded
back into the fourth round uh when there
were some available. Why did do you
think it wasn't in your best interest to
take one?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think it's a good
question. Um, so there were a couple
centers that we really liked. Um, the
guys that went in the second round. And
I think after that, you know, could we
have traded up, you know, potentially
maybe traded up into the second round
and maybe take one of those guys? And we
we really assessed it like where we were
picking at 80 for us to do that would
have cost our second round pick, our
third round pick and our fourth round
pick points wise to do that. Um, but
know third round, fourth round, fifth
round, whatever you're going to say
pointswise to do it. probably
prohibitive for us to get up that high
in the draft. And so, you know, um would
I rather have Jacobe,
uh Serat, and uh and and and Hibner? I
probably would than one player at that
point. So, it was impossible for us to
really get back up into the second round
unless we gave up a first round pick
next year, maybe potentially. Um, you
know, there were some other centers, but
there was nobody that we looked at that
we thought necessarily like this guy's
going to come in here and, you know, I'm
not good players, but there's nobody
that's going to necessarily be an impact
player for us this year. Um, I do think
we'll have a plan um at the position.
Feel confident in saying that. And I
think we have a couple guys here that
will compete for that position. But um
as the uh a hall of fame general manager
once said um you don't play games till
September and I think we'll have a great
offensive line at that point. We have a
plan. Uh it didn't necessarily fall our
way this weekend, but it's still early
and I'm thrilled with what we'll be able
to accomplish. Derek, were you surprised
that the two guys win as early as they
did? Those first two centers.
>> I was uh I was a little surprised. Um
I would probably attribute that to the
run on offensive linemen in the first
and second round and that trickle down
effect. Um because uh you know, you saw
those tackles and guards go um you know
that's what happens. I I think you see
it you saw it in a different way this
year with receiver and tight ends. And
so again, you saw these receivers get
picked and then you saw a huge run on
tight ends. Um these teams have to
adjust quickly on the fly. So, um I
think actually one of the one of the
centers that was drafted got turned in
as a guard. Um just because all those
guards got picked and so now as a team
you're trying to look at it and go, "Oh
man, how are we going to fill this guard
position? Well, let's take this center.
He can probably play guard." So it's
hard. It's challenging. Um, a lot of
times when you find yourself in a
position like that, and we've been in
this many years, is it's just the pick
that you have, the number that you have,
um, and not just being able to maneuver,
uh, the right way or not not having the
ammunition,
um, or maybe the the cost of doing so is
probably prohibitive. So, unfortunate,
but I'm ecstatic with the players that
we're able to get. And um honestly like
looking at this list of players, I
probably wouldn't do anything
differently.
>> For for you or for Jesse, what what is
your guys plan now with Emry? Is someone
Is he someone who you're still looking
at at guard or a tackle or is he someone
who could even potentially have a shot
at center?
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, coming out, he was a
right tackle and he's a damn good right
tackle. Um we think he's going to be a
damn good guard, too. um coming off the
injury. We think he's a talented guy,
great mentality, great makeup. Um and
you know, he's going to compete. He'll
compete to start and we're going to have
great depth and we're going to have a
great six-man. I don't know who that
sixman's going to be, but whoever it is,
if you come out of it in with this
group, you're going to be really
talented. You're going to be really
good. So, I like the depth that we have
right now. We still have some moves to
make. I think we're in a much better
place than we have been. Um, and I'm
excited to see what happens.
>> Jesse, I know you were kind of
non-committal in terms of venue where he
would play, but I mean, does he have
that? I knew he played a little bit of
center. That's something you guys would
even look at.
>> Yeah, I think we'll start off thinking
more of a guard, but I think there's
always I I really think coach Leadford
does a great job. Um, highly confident
that we'll be able to put a great O line
together. I do think there will be a
there's the thought of how do you get
your best five guys on the field, you
know, no different than a guy like
secondary or, you know, linebackers.
It's like how do you how do you get the
best players that can help you win onto
the field and so I think that's the
great part about the offseason getting a
chance to work with these guys. It's a
it's a good time sometimes to experiment
with with people like that and see what
see the versatility that guys have. Uh
and then again come September, you know,
figure out figure out where where
everybody fits best, where they can best
thrive and succeed and uh help us have
the best O line.
>> Jesse, um Eric mentioned yesterday three
guys. I mean, Z Pinter, Vaughn, and um
>> are those the three guys you talked
about?
>> Yeah, those three guys for sure. I think
uh we feel good about those guys
competing. Um, and then again, just like
all the guys, all the interior, all the
offensive linemen, having that ability
to potentially, you know, showcase some
versatility and play different spots and
and us figure out the best five, the
best six, the best seven, the best
eight, you know, that'll be a major work
in progress between now and September.
>> Jesse, when you sort of step back and
look at the 11 guys you drafted over the
last three days, do you see any sort of
theme that runs through the entire
class?
um you know, tough, physical, you know,
a lot of those these guys are big
physical players. Um when you look at
when you look at the O line, obviously
you start with Venga and just like him
setting the tone for the draft class. Um
dominant line of scrimmage and so think
we added, you know, the best interior
interior offensive lineman in the draft.
Um Zion again, big physical, tough,
rugged player. Jacobe, big matchup guy.
Size, speed, length, catch radius,
ability to make tough plays. Um, I mean,
Srod as well, like that was a really
cool opportunity to double dip at that
position. The way the board fell and
taking the best guy, a guy that's had a
ton of production in major impact games
the last two years at Indiana. And then
I I think when guys are really
productive wherever they're playing, you
know, he played a year at a JMU, he
played a year at even a smaller school
before that. A super productive player.
U Hibner, you know, I mean, I've seen
this guy in some really bloody physical
nine on sevens, you know, two, three,
four years ago. Um being a really
physical blocker, even maybe more so
than showed up in and what they were
asking him to do at SMU. Uh again,
excited about him. Uh, but all the guys,
I mean, you you can go all the way down
the list. Even Chandler Rivers, not as
big in in stature, but plays with a
really cool mindset. Love the way that
guy plays football. Attacks the ball,
plays really physical. He's a good
tackler for his size. Um, so I just
think you go all the way down the list.
Um, it's a really physical group. Big,
big, strong, tough, physical team that
we're trying to trying to have here. And
all these guys fit that bill. Jesse, um
it's been probably a blur these couple
months of everything you've had on your
plate. What was this experience like in
your new role with all the first you're
experiencing? And what's kind of a
general takeaway for you just being part
of your first draft as a head coach?
>> Yeah, it was incredible. Uh you know,
this is the this is the obviously we
talked about this all the way back, but
like this is the job I wanted because
the people here and how they operate and
Eric does an amazing job. Uh you got
Azie Newsome sitting in there. You got
Steve Bashadotti. Just people that are
unbelievable. Uh you know, people first
and then they they can just manage
situations. They got a great mind for
what's happening throughout the draft.
They've done a great job of bringing the
coaches in. And I feel like everybody on
the staff really felt value and felt
input into how we ended up with these
players, you know, which I think is a
cool quality to have to to make to bring
people in and make it make it
collaborative. Um, but at the end of the
day, man, it's just a cool, really cool
situation to kind of see the team come
together. Um, you know, when you go into
it, there's, I think, you know, 50 so
players on our team and you add 11 and
then obviously we'll add more the rest
of the day. It'll be really exciting
when we look out there and there's uh 90
guys on the roster.
>> What was there a position that Eric kind
of tasked you with evaluating specific
prospect class?
>> You know, it was really cool. I I've
always taken really a lot of pride as an
evaluator. Um it was it was honestly
really neat and fun to to do a lot of
different positions um over the time and
so first time really evaluating like
offensive linemen and wide receivers in
a way in a different way than just
preparing to play against them. Um, you
know, and and and to me, like the things
that jump out as a as a defensive
history coach, I would say, you know,
the play style and how these guys play
and just like the down after down
mindset that they play with when you're
looking at offensive players really
jumps off the tape with all these guys.
Their ability to make tough, especially
like the the playmakers, the skilled
players, their ability to make tough
plays, contested plays, key plays on the
field in the red area. both these guys,
both these wide receivers, huge red zone
uh targets. So, just fun to evaluate all
the different positions and look at
different things. Um, and then
certainly, you know, the secondary has
probably always been a knack of mine to
try to get some of those guys.
>> Eric, uh, obviously you have very
detailed records of of all these guys
and their various idiosyncrasies, but,
you know, you look at your two receivers
in in Jacobe and Elijah and then your
two tight ends. Um, you know, very sort
of similar on the surface profiles for
each of those positions. I mean, high
point, you know, tall receivers and
tight ends or maybe sort of tweener
types who have blocking ability and then
some, you know, pass catching.
>> Are there ways in which those guys sort
of diverge from each other or is the
overlap some of the point and why you
decided to draft them?
Yeah, I think the the biggest thing I
think is just that we they're they're
versatile players that do some really
good things. Um they're not exactly the
same. You know, our vision for Jacobe is
probably a little bit different than
maybe the vision for Sarat. They're
going to compete for playing time,
right? They both catch the ball really
well. They're both big. Um but they're
not exactly identical. I think u you
know Matt and Josh um they're a little
different. They're a little different
how they're used and the offense is
different, but I love the fact that
they're both versatile players who can
do different things. And in our offense,
not to not to give a lot away, and I
don't even understand our offense yet to
be honest, but I know that versatility
and flexibility and being able to do a
lot of different things is really
important. Being smart, being adaptable,
um is really, really important. The idea
of deception and all these things and
just flexibility to play multiple roles,
I think, is really a plus. And so, um,
you know, and then just being able to
handle the physical aspect of the game,
being tough, being tough minded, being
able to handle adversity, um, you know,
uh, again, like I talked a little bit
yesterday about this, but I had a bunch
of other players reach out to me today
um about some of these guys and just
they know their stories and I think
these guys were made, you know, of the
right stuff, most of these guys and I
want to thank for that. I just think
it's opportunity for me to thank the
scouts specifically um the area guys and
then also um couple unheralded guys um
Steve Claget and Derek Yam as well. They
do a lot of work on the draft in
different ways um George and Mark and
all those guys and and Nick. But we get
great information on how these guys kind
of who they are as people, background,
motivations, drivers and all those
different things. and the scouts and and
those guys upstairs, they're really the
guys that are able to kind of put that
all together for me to help me make the
decisions. And so without that, this
process would be much more complicated
and probably not as not as accurate. So
>> sort of on the topic of versatility, um
you know, Declan comes from the Shawn
Payeyton school and Shawn's offense.
Think of Taesm Hill as sort of a do it
all jack knife type guy. I think you use
the word jack knife when describing
Adam. um you know as a receiver turned
running back. I mean is there sort of a
Joker jack knife role or that he could
kind of be in the running for that's new
to this offense?
>> Well I think that remains to be seen but
I will say he's very smart. He's big.
He's athletic. He catches the ball well.
He runs good routes. He's physical. He's
a physical runner. He's played special
teams. He can return kicks. So his value
it does get it does get magnified. And I
think uh not not to speak for coach, but
one of the hardest things to do is is
come up with a 48man roster and uh if
you have guys who can do multiple
things, it really makes your job a lot
easier because now you can you can you
can create roles for other people
because you might have a player who can
do more than just one thing. So if you
can run routes, run the ball, pass,
protect, and return kicks, now your
value really skyrockets. Eric, I know
you were uh dialed in to the whole
draft, but did you get a chuckle out of
watching uh Mark Ingram's son or the
lady from uh the UK?
>> We did. We laughed. We saw that, you
know. Um yeah, it was it was great. I
mean, Mark, you know, he's I think
someone said it, but you know, you'd
think that Mark spent his whole career
with us. He's only with us two years,
but they were memorable years and that
19 season especially, he's got a special
place in my heart and I think of him as
a as a real original Raven, even though
obviously he played more more years in
New Orleans. And so guy that I really
respect, I love his passion. I thought
was really funny. Um, and you know,
certainly I think the uh back and forth
between, you know, Pittsburgh and
Baltimore, we we saw that this weekend,
right? And I think that's is kind of
actually a special thing, right? It's
kind of fun that we have that type of
rivalry that's like celebrated across
the country. Everybody understands like
what it's like Red Sox, Yankees, you
know. Um, everybody understands it and
kind of celebrates it. I think it's one
of the things that makes sports special.
>> How's the scouting process compared to
find equally this year after you're
looking for a kicker last year in the
pre-draft?
>> Oh man. Well, I don't get involved in
that too much, you know. Um, and I'm not
I don't want to, you know, I don't want
to create a monster, but he's already
been created, you know, he's already
been created. Uh, but Randy does a
phenomenal job. He does. And so, um,
it's probably the one the two positions
that if Randy comes to me and says,
"This is the guy that we need," I'm
going to accept it. Normally I'd be like
a little skeptical and I want to watch
the tape and do my homework and put my
eyes on the guy, but when Randy does
this and says, "Yeah, this is the best
one." Then that resonates and um you
know, I think our track record with
kickers and pawners is pretty good. Long
snappers is pretty good. Um so it's not
something I'm going to mess with. So,
um,
now I might fight with him as to when we
have to draft the guy or what round, but
as far as like being the best at
ranking, I think he's the best at that.
>> Do you look at Monday, I guess Monday at
4 after that, um, free agent signings no
longer counter the comp formula. You're
fond of saying that building a roster is
sort of an everyday thing year round. Do
you view this almost as another phase of
free agency for this team?
We do. Um
yeah, I mean, you know, we don't have
any agreements that would be illegal, of
course. Um but there's always there
always players out there that you can go
after that you'll try to talk to at some
point. And as you the draft is really,
you know, you kind of you you go through
this process and now you know what the
roster looks like. So now it's easy next
week to go out and say, "Okay, we need
this, we might need this, we might need
this." Um, so I think with free agency,
potentially trades, um, terminated
players, you know, we still June 1st
still at risk for players to be
terminated. There were opportunity for
us to sign a few guys. And as you guys
know, like even I remember, you know, I
think uh I don't know what year that
was, but 2021,
maybe 22,
I was at driving up to Penn State with
my daughter and we signed uh I
negotiated the contract for Javian
Clowney in the car. That was in August.
So I think it was in August, right? It
was in August. Yeah. So those things can
happen, right? And so again, it's like
we try to be patient, not be uh too
reactive to things, not overreact, just
to be patient, and we'll see what
happens. Let good players fall to us.
There's going to be opportunities coming
along, and we'll be ready to pounce.
Jesse,
>> how have you seen Raan Benny progress
both when you were with him in Michigan
and since then?
>> Yeah, Ray's a u tough, rugged, physical
defensive lineman that's got some real
athleticism. I think there's some real
upside there with him and some pass rush
ability. Uh he got thought in 2023 he
was our third or fourth type defensive
lineman. We had Mason and Kenneth Grant
and Chris Jenkins and we had obviously a
pretty loaded group. Um but he made some
really key plays for us in that season.
He got hurt in the Rose Bowl that year.
Um and it I know it affected him. I was
gone after that. But I thought this year
he really bounced back after kind of
battling through the injury in 2024.
Showed some really good stuff. does a
lot of things on tape that that
obviously we like to see. Um, and so I
think he's just kind of a guy that's
gotten better and better. He was really
really raw and kind of a young player
coming into Michigan. Um, but uh those
guys there, you know, I know he's been
well trained and and well coached and uh
excited to add Ray.
>> Jesse, we didn't get a chance to ask you
about your voluntary mini camp you were
able to have this past week. what stood
out about that in terms of you know guys
attendance and just what did you learn
about your football team getting to have
most of them together for the first
time?
>> Yeah, I mean it was unbelievable
turnout. Uh we had a great three days
together. I think we learned a lot about
each other just kind of how we're
operating on the practice field. some of
the things that we're doing. We didn't
do a ton of full speed team work in that
just from a health and safety standpoint
of where we're at in the offseason
program, but the guys had a real
opportunity to kind of see where they're
at learning the learning new schemes on
both sides of the ball. Um, and so it
was it was incredible. It was a lot of
fun. Um, it was cool to see the coaches
out there coaching these guys up. We
kind of knew it kind of gives you a
especially going into the draft, it
gives you a little bit of sense at
different positions and kind of where
you're at. Um, and so it's a it's a
great rule. I do I do love that for new
staffs to be able to have that
opportunity. And uh now we go right back
into phase two and uh continue to try to
get better.
>> Eric, um since we're not actually talk
to you until September now, uh any
anything you can tell us about uh
progress with Lamar and contract talks?
>> No, not really.
Okay. Thank you.